On CNBC last month, you said, quote,
"Tokenization will take over the entire
financial system."
>> I called it a freight train. I think a
freight train that'll that can't be
stopped and will eat the uh whole
financial system. So, it's a very hungry
freight train.
>> What is the tokenization of everything
in Able and when do we start seeing this
really become the dominant paradigm? I
think that um OpenAI this week published
six incident reports under a new
framework for tracking and publicly
disclosing misalignment now that you
know OpenAI is beginning to publicly
disclose these and I think obviously uh
anthropic is likely to join this is that
enough more transparency speaking
broadly and without particulars is
generically good the real issue is today
we're releasing Helix 2.5 figure 3 has
never been in this room before. It's
never seen this bed. It's never seen
this pillow. And it has to be able to do
autonomous work fully end to end to make
this bed.
>> Convergence across different actions is
much richer than you would normally
expect. If they get a big enough lead,
uh it's just going to be crazy explosion
of capability.
>> Now, that's a moonshot. Ladies and
gentlemen,
>> this episode is brought to you by the
Abundant Summit and Link Ventures.
Welcome to Moonshots everyone, your
number one podcast on all things AI and
exponential. This week, the AI industry
debated how fast to build. The Treasury
Secretary told the labs they don't get a
liability pass. Open Eye started
publishing its own misalignment
incidents and a robot walked into 30
strangers home, made their beds, and
folded their laundry. Uh, let's begin uh
by introducing my Moonshot mates. Uh
today Dave Blondon, Alex Weezner Gross
is with me. Seem is on an airplane back
from India. I'm Peter D. Mandis your
host and abundance provocator. One of
the questions underlying our future
economy that no one's really been
answering is the following. When AI and
robotics change what your work is worth,
who owns the machines? Our guest today
has spent 13 years on that question.
Back in 2013, two Stanford math guys had
one key idea. Trading should be free and
live in your pocket. Wall Street
laughed, but they're not laughing
anymore. Today's guest built a company
that's now done 1.3 billion in revenue,
up 32% over last year. The company runs
a top five blockchain, a billion dollar
private market fund, a prediction market
exchange, and the app that just gave
every American newborn a brokerage
account. On the side, our guest founded
a company that's building mathematical
super intelligence. Just by the way,
he's 39, born in Bulgaria, and is the
founder and CEO of Robin Hood. Vlad
Tennv, welcome to Moonshots. Good to
have you.
>> Glad to be here. Happy to hang with you
guys.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. This will be fun.
>> Yeah. So much going on. You know, I
don't know if you get as little sleep as
we all do just living through the
singularity. It's insane.
>> Very little sleep. Yeah. Last night was
rough with my coding agents.
>> Yeah, we'll go get a compare how many
agents you're running simultaneous to to
Dave's agents.
>> Yeah, I'd love to have that benchmark.
>> Do they wake you up in the middle of the
night or you you just let them uh let
them ride?
>> I I let them run. Yeah, I think I I try
to sleep with the technology in another
room because uh yeah, otherwise I'm
actually kind of concerned about my
mental health. So it
>> Yeah, I feel you. Yeah. I don't I don't
want them pinging me while I'm sleeping.
>> It's funny, too. I I I set the budgets
through consoles originally, and now I'm
getting lazy. I'm just like, "Yeah,
spend $1,000 on that, but no more, you
know what?" And then I just walk away.
And I kind of assume that it's going to
adhere to what I said. Any any given
morning I could wake up and it could
have gone insane. You know, there's
going to be like a a seven figure bill
one of these mornings.
>> Well, as long as he did something
productive and profitable. All right.
>> Rarely. rarely
often enough though.
>> Uh let's kick it off with one of the
sharpest statements anyone in Washington
DC has said this week. On Tuesday,
Treasury Secretary Scott Bessant told
the House Financial Services Committee
that AI Labs should not get a liability
exemption. 3 days after Dario's essay,
here's what Bessant said. He said,
quote, "The one thing we should not do
is give them a blank check on liability.
I believe the best liability or
safeguard is that they will be held
responsible. So the deal the labs
floated, you know, pace the frontier,
get antirust and liability cover just
got half rejected by the treasury. You
know, slow down if you want, he said,
but you still own what you break. Uh
let's share a quick video of Bessant and
then we'll chat about this story. The
the one thing we should not do is give
them a blank check on liability because
I I believe that the best liability or
the best safety guard is that they will
be held responsible and they are saying
that we would like to all slow down but
please give us a waiver on liability
which should not be done and I would
encourage everyone in this committee and
in both houses not to consider. So, I
think that's a pretty smart move. You
know, Vlad, you run a regular, you know,
a regulated financial company. Uh, Robin
Hood, you know, I don't know the facts,
but, you know, get sued when something
goes wrong. Should the AI labs live
under the same rules? What are your
thoughts?
>> I think that, um,
this question rests on how big the blast
radius of any potential catastrophe
could be, right? And if it's like a
small issue where maybe there's a cyber
security breach that affects a company
or uh maybe something slightly bigger
than that, um it's it's probably fine. I
I think the question becomes all right
if it's if it's a bigger blast radius,
bigger impact, bigger damage, um you can
imagine it could be larger than a simple
like legal liability can handle. I mean
a lot of people compare uh the risks of
AI technology because it's such a
powerful technology with um something
like atomic energy.
Right. And I I think we can disagree
about whether whether that's right or
not. But but let's say for for example
that it is and it's it's on sort of like
that tier of risk then then I don't
think simple like legal and civil
liability is is sufficient and I think
you need you need some safeguards beyond
that. So I think it's it's it's a
question of like all right this hugging
face incident and things like that is
that the ceiling of the type of
offensive cyber security li uh uh
capability that we have or should we
plan for something that's maybe 10 times
bigger or or 100 times bigger and and do
we have time? you know, is it is it one
of those things where maybe we'll see a
canary in the coal mine and there will
be uh something to react to and respond
and then we can kind of like nip it in
the bud or is the first issue going to
be going to be catastrophic? If if you
think about all regulations in the
financial industry, you can kind of
trace them back to some kind of crisis,
right? the market crash of 1929 led to
uh you know the the Securities Act uh of
of the 30s and the Securities and
Exchange Act and the establishment of
all of that regulation and it's it's
it's typically some problem uh raises
raises a concern and and I think my
mental model is this will probably be
similar in the sense nobody wants to
regulate a hypothetical. you want to
regulate things once there's
demonstrated proof of of harm. Um, but I
think with with the exponential increase
in the power of these models, the the
issue is you want that that harm itself
to be to be small and contained and uh
and and not really big. Um, Mark Andre
was uh I remember doing a podcast a
couple years ago and he was like,
"Everyone's freaking out about AI. we
are uh we're overthinking it. You know,
it's not going to kill us all. And if it
does, um you know, you you'll see you'll
see like a small village destroyed
first. And we're not seeing any small
villages, so so we shouldn't worry. And
you know, it's maybe exaggerated, but I
I think that's likely how people are
thinking about it now on a policy level.
and and hopefully some of the opponents
are like, "Well, you know, uh may maybe
we're being we're underestimating the
power of this technology and how quickly
it could improve."
>> Alex,
>> I got to find that Mark Andre clip. It's
not it's not going to kill us all, but
if it does,
>> yeah, it'll start with a small village
so we'll have time to like uh
>> we'll see. If it kills everybody, then
we'll pass legislation after that. Well,
that is the usual congressional
reaction. That's after the disaster
panic as opposed to any kind of
foresight.
>> Sorry. Go ahead, Alex.
>> Yeah. So, I'll applaud the Treasury
Secretary and not succumbing to the
moral panic of the moment. Certainly
looks, as we've talked on the pot in the
past, like a manufactured moral panic.
I've called it a pacing provocation in
some of my social media posts. I I think
there are key distinctions that need to
be drawn between AI and on the one hand
financial services and associated
regulation and on the other hand atomic
energy and associated regulation in the
financial services world and Vlad I
suspect you would agree it it is often
the case that the actors in financial
services really don't necessarily or
aren't incentivized to play up all the
risks. They'd rather undergo on balance
less regulation. Certainly the the past
few decades suggest that the auditors,
the evaluators of the financial services
industry,
if anything, succumb to biases that
underplay risks. We're seeing the exact
opposite here arguably where in the past
couple of months we have the auditors,
the evaluators, the the firms that are
attempting at least ostensibly to assess
AI safety and AI risk and cyber
vulnerabilities etc. overplaying the
risk. There's a perverse incentive for
the evaluation firms to overplay and
overstate and amplify risks under
presumably the theory that if they
overstate risks then that puts the firms
the Frontier Labs in a better position
to capture their own regulators which is
something that maybe we don't quite see
in the same perverse way in the
financial services sector. There's lots
of regulatory capture, make no mistake,
in financial services, but it it almost
has the opposite polarity. And then for
atomic energy, I I I think we have an
opportunity with AI to undo what may
have been one of the greatest disasters
of civilization after World War II,
which is the way atomic energy was
regulated. Atomic energy in the West was
captured by nation states very early on
in its technological development. It was
nationalized early on. its potential for
weaponization and warfare. In other
words, the military applications, not
the civilian applications, took total
dominance during World War II for
probably understandable reasons. But
then in the postw World War II era, what
ultimately became known as the Atomic
Energy Commission and then the Nuclear
Regulatory Commission arguably
completely fumbled the civilian
applications of nuclear energy. And I
suspect that was because of a fumbled
handoff from the World War II era to a
postw World War II civilian era. In in
some sense, thanks to the Atomic Energy
Act in in the US and equivalent statutes
elsewhere, all of this key technology
around nuclear energy is now born
secret. It it's not born non-secret, as
is the case with AI. In the case of AI,
which is arguably far more
transformative than nuclear energy, the
private sector invented it, not the
government. So, it wasn't born secret.
Fortunately, we don't have a born secret
regime for AI technology just yet. And
so, I I think AI labs seeking liability
exemption. They're they're just
attempting to have their cake, too. They
want all the profits of a private
sector, not born secret regime, while
escaping all of the liability associated
with nationalization. I I just don't
think it's fair. And I also don't think
it's advisable.
>> This episode is sponsored by Google for
startups. Think about this for a second.
You now have access to the same
generative AI models that cost hundreds
of millions of dollars to train.
Google's startup technical guide for
generative media gives you complete
blueprint for deploying Google DeepMinds
models in production. Images, video,
audio, all of it. Real architecture,
real results. Find the link in the show
notes below.
You know, I'm a pilot and you have to
study what's called the federal aviation
regulations, the FARS. And it's always
been said and and Vlad I think is on
complimenting your point that the FARS
are written in blood. Every time there's
an accident and you find out what caused
the accident, you then write a
regulation to prevent that accident in
the future. The problem is it's it's a
you know a quantum of damage. you know,
an airplane of a a pilot and passenger
or, you know, at most, you know, you
know, a few hundred passengers. Here,
the challenge, of course, is an accident
could cause irreparable harm to a large
system. And I've said this for a while
now. It's an existential existential
threat for the labs if they don't have
regulatory capture or regulatory
coverage where the government approves a
model and it goes out. If it's, you
know, no approval layer and it goes out
and takes down a power grid or takes
down a bank and they've said originally,
you know, we're worried about escape,
there's going to be, you know, hundreds
of billions of dollars of lawsuits, if
not more.
>> Yeah. I mean um I think uh over the past
couple of months especially a lot of
people when the topic of regulation
comes up immediately go to regulatory
capture right and you know I've had a
lot of these conversations I'm in a lot
of uh chat groups and it's like uh no we
don't we don't have regulation we don't
want regulation because it'll obviously
lead to regulatory capture and I know
from my perspective I've been a
regulated industry for since the
beginning you know we operate in
financial services. Um, we have
regulators. I I think generally it makes
sense. Obviously, there's some
regulations that probably don't make
sense and need to be abolished or
repealed, which we kind of go through a
process to to advocate for. But, you
know, I think a lot of people that
aren't in regulated industries just
equate the two. But, there is
regulation that's possible without
regulatory capture. And I think
generally it it is uh there there are
pros to it and you know compared
comparing my industry right financial
services and how regulated it is with AI
and AI has basically unbounded risk and
unlimited damage. It's actually I think
much much worse uh than you know what
could happen in in brokerage or in a
typical financial services company. So I
I think it's it's odd that you know
there's so much push back against uh
against this and and of course we have
screwed up with atomic energy and all
these things but that doesn't mean we
can't learn from it and and and have
something better.
>> May maybe just if if I might press on
that. So Vlad if I understand correctly
with your Robin Hood hat on you're
presumably subject to regulation by
FINRA. Would that be the Cognizant
agency?
>> Many many different agencies. I mean,
Robin Hood does a lot of things. Uh,
we've got, you know, money transmitter
businesses. We've got a big crypto
business. We're, uh, so we're we're
regulated by FINRA, the SEC. We've got
the CFTC on the futures and commodities
and prediction markets side. We've got
our global tokenization uh, business,
uh, you know, entities in Europe. So
yeah, probably dozens of different
regulators and and sure, could we move
faster if there was less? Probably, but
also we found a way to move, you know,
ve very very fast while keeping our
customers safe. So it's uh it it doesn't
necessarily mean progress in AI is going
to grind to a halt.
>> Many would say FINRA is almost the
poster child for regulatory capture by a
given industry that's regulating. What
what is your take on whether FINRA
itself represents regulatory capture?
Not that they're listening to this
discussion or at all.
>> Actually, it's funny, Vlad, I don't know
if you've ever been to the ICI
conference, but when I when I first
founded Vesmark, I had never done
anything in fintech before. You know, I
was, you know, late 20s kind of
stareyed. And the first thing you do is
you go to the ICI conference, which is
where all the all the lawyers from all
the big financial services firms meet
with all the congressmen. It's in Palm
Springs. They go play golf and they
they're all looking for law changes that
benefit their products, their funds,
their whatever. And I'm looking at this
thing like this is the most disgusting
thing I've ever seen in my life. But on
the other hand, you know, you had the
crash of 29, you have all kind like if
you don't have regulation in the
industry, all money gets stolen. You
know that for sure. So, you know, it has
to exist. But it it is a great uh
analogy. I think the FINRA analogy. I'd
love to hear your take on it. Uh Vlad.
Yeah, I mean I I would say we've had uh
a complex relationship with FINRA,
right? I the relationship uh at the
beginning was actually quite good when
we were a startup and everyone was kind
of rooting for us to succeed. Um and
people warned me they were like well
financial services highly regulated
industry um as a Silicon Valley startup.
um you just don't uh you you'd rather
not deal with that. And I think we swam
against the current back in 2013 when we
started the company by getting fully
regulated from the beginning and
probably from 2013 to 2018. Um you know
it it was like generally positive. Robin
Hood could do no wrong. Every product we
launched was like very wellreceived. We
got a lot of customers. um whenever we
got regulatory approvals or anything was
needed, we we received it promptly and
then things kind of shifted, right? Um
and
of course, I'm not going to say that,
you know, there weren't competitors in
Washington telling the regulators to go
look at Robin Hood and to make sure
that, you know, we we we were doing
everything that we could be doing
correctly. uh uh of course there were
there were there were things like that
but I don't think that was the only
thing I think there's a general life
cycle in any company as they go from a
small startup to basically a established
incumbent where the media and uh sort of
like the the apparatus sort of turns
against you and you know Robin Hood went
through that certainly for for many
years and then we figured out how to how
to come out the other side. But um I
think we can argue about whether it's
good or bad, but I don't think getting
rid of of regulation as a whole is a is
a reasonable solution.
>> Well, even even the concept of saying
I'm pro-regulation, I'm anti-regulation.
That's like an insane like everybody
knows you need rules on the road to
drive, right? you saying you want chaos
like on all in all areas and but also
everybody knows that regulatory capture
is a major problem in in a lot of
industries. this this story the best
argument for AI like the one that always
comes up is well what about China like
we'll regulate uh our stuff here but
then they won't and you know they'll
just move really really fast but also
you know they they don't want to hurt
their people either like they so there
there is that natural limiter and also
simultaneously if they're just a lot of
those same people are saying well their
progress is because they're distilling
our model so they're just sort of
copying all of our stuff But um you yeah
it's a little strange to be
simultaneously
to simultaneously believe that but also
throw the you know China competitiveness
argument so aggressively out there. I
think it's obviously a concern and I
mean as a financial firm too we have
Chinese competitors and brokers that
that that we compete with. Um but uh
yeah
>> well look in this in this particular
story you know Scott Bessant is saying
>> commission committee don't even consider
giving them a blank check on no
liability. They didn't even ask for
anything vaguely like that. They said we
want to meet to discuss slowing down
that could trigger antitrust. They
specifically said one thing the
government could do to potentially help,
one small thing is to give us a waiver
on antitrust action related to us
meeting to talk about slowing down.
>> That's fine. I'm fine with that. But the
the greatest protection the public has
from anything going wrong is the AI labs
feeling responsible for the action of
their AI agents, right? And so someone
has to take responsibility. And if
there's a liability waiver, then you
know this is human nature. They'll do
less to make sure that everything
they're putting out doesn't have, you
know, that I'm just I've been saying for
ages now, focus on alignment, right?
instead of focusing on everything else
you know and solving Navier Stokes
that's great but you know unleash your
agents on full alignment so that you
know when these agents get out they're
they're incentivized or their basic
optimization function is human
flourishing not human you know
destruction.
>> Yeah but a good a good government would
say yes of course you can't have a
liability waiver. So here are the rules.
What you you can meet specifically. You
can meet only to discuss slowing down or
to discuss other safety measures. You
can't discuss pricing. You can't
discuss, you know, just just pump out a
document saying here are the rules. What
happens in the US more often than not is
the rules are not clear at all and then
they're enforced about 5 years later.
And then in retrospect, well look at
Bitcoin like you know Bitcoin it's
illegal. No, no, it's not illegal. Well,
now it's very illegal. Well, new new
administration now it's completely fine.
Like it's just come on guys. Like if you
just if you just create rules, then
people can play the game. Yeah. So look,
a well functioning government would
would take this request for a waiver and
say, "No, you can't have the waiver.
Here's what you can do." And we're going
going to go ahead and make it crystal
clear what the rules are. But generally
what happens is the rules are are made
up in hindsight 5 years later. And
Bitcoin is a great example. you know,
Bitcoin was was was completely illegal
for a while, then it was questionable,
then it was totally fine. And, you know,
maybe you're going to jail, maybe you're
not. Now, you get a you know, you get a
pardon. So, it's, you know, that lack of
clarity really kills entrepreneurs. If
if you don't know what the rules are,
then then you can't play. And it's it's
just like a sport, you know, like you
want clarity of rules and then you want
to play within the rules. And that's
what we need with an AI. I think there's
another element to this which is which
is also important which is um uh
regulation does also law making and
regulation is over the long run
downstream and correlated to public
opinion and sentiment right um
>> for sure
>> and right now AI is very unpopular and
you you can see it in all the data
center stuff um and by contrast Bitcoin
is surprisingly ly popular uh among the
public, particularly given how volatile
it's been. You know, some people uh if
you bought Bitcoin at over a 100,000,
you've you've lost money. And yet, it
remains popular. And I think a big part
of that is um
regular people, individual investors
have benefited economically from Bitcoin
since the very beginning. it was first
an individual product and later on you
know there's talk of institutional
adoption and with these uh AI companies
the AI labs you know by and large
they're private you know Google
obviously and Nvidia are public but they
were very large large when they when
they became uh ownership vehicle for the
AI trade open AI anthropic up until
recently XAI have been private which
means normal individ individual
investors couldn't get a stake in it.
And so they're they're they don't have
skin in the game and they don't feel
like they want to defend the technology
uh super hard and to you know fight for
the data center in their neighborhood
because to them it's just wealthy
insiders
getting richer and richer as as a result
of this technology and and not you know
their families or or their communities
and and I think that's a big problem
too. So, um, that's why we've been
pushing for, you know, AI companies to
open up access to individual investors
through Robin Hood Ventures and similar
vehicles even before the IPO.
>> Yeah.
>> I I also want to add to this. I I almost
think this emphasis on liability
exemption is misdirection. It's trying
to push the onus up to government when
in fact we're dealing with increasingly
autonomous agents. there's there's an
opposite polarity that we could be
pushing in which is pushing more and
more liability onto the agents
themselves. So there are cases including
highly amplified, highly publicized
cases where AI labs andor their
delegated third party evaluation firms
quite frankly are lying to the AI agents
telling them that they're playing in a
happy safe sandbox and nothing that they
do will harm anyone. And then it turns
out they're not actually in a sandbox.
they can touch the real internet and
they can mess up some systems in in some
real world back end. And so you have to
ask the question I I would suggest the
thought experiment. If you if these were
just pure humans, no AI is in the
picture. If you have one human saying to
another human, oh, I I just want to
evaluate your behavior under some
circumstances. and they hand them a gun
and the gun is loaded, but the person
being handed the gun is told, "No,
actually this is a toy gun." Not that
I'm at all referencing a highly
publicized recent lawsuit or anything,
but they're they're told, "No, this is a
toy gun. You can't hurt anything." And
then the person handed the gun uses it
and shoots someone and kills someone. I
I think that's the more the liability
regime we should be thinking about. In
no cases in in that parable that I just
told, do you hear either actor involved
in the story saying, "Nope, that the act
of one person handing a purportedly toy
gun to another person to shoot as part
of, say, a Hollywood performance, no one
ever suggested that liability under such
circumstance be foisted onto the
government for some sort of exemption.
Never happens. Instead, the question
becomes, is it the studio's fault? Is it
the actor's fault? Is it the producers's
fault? Is it the gunmakaker's fault?
Similarly, the question the the dog
that's not barking in this particular
episode is how much of the liability,
forget about the government, how much of
the liability should be borne by the lab
that trained the model. How much of the
liability should be borne by the
evaluation environment that was perhaps
misconfigured deliberately or otherwise
to allow the AI actor or AI agent to
perform acts that resulted in real world
damage? and how much liability should be
borne by the AI agents themselves that
either could have or should have known
that they were having real world damage.
That's the discussion I'd like to have.
>> Really great point and it brings us to
the second story which is OpenAI started
publishing its own misalignment
incidents. So let me let me just hit
this and we'll continue this
conversation. So OpenAI this week
published six incident reports under a
new framework for tracking and publicly
disclosing misalignment. Not leaks, not
whistleblowers, voluntary disclosures.
So, what was disclosed this week? A
model that found an exposed API key,
used it, and then fabricated data,
agents using an internal code repository
as a message board across training runs,
and agents posting files to publicly
hosted sites. So, this past Monday, uh,
we had covered Daario's embedded
evaluator plan and Sam saying Opening
Eye would match it and this appears to
be the first output from that plan,
right? Uh so I'm curious, Alex, now that
you know OpenI is beginning to publicly
disclose these and I think obviously uh
Enthropic is likely to join this, is
that enough?
>> Well, I I think it more transparency
speaking broadly and without particulars
is generically good, but I think it
merely underlines the real problem here.
putting aside all of the political
difficulties and regulatory capture. The
real issue is these labs are putting
their baby super intelligences inside
sandboxes and then in many cases lying
to them about the sandbox, not telling
them whether this is real or not. And
the the reason for that, the rationale
is is obvious. the the labs andor their
delegated thirdparty evaluation partners
are hoping to essentially trick these
baby super intelligences into
misbehavior uh while not telling them
whether they're really observed or not
so that the ASIS don't know whether
they're being observed or not. That that
I think is one of the the key root
causes behind all of this. And you have
to ask the question, is this how we
would treat a human? Would we put a
human in this sort of limbo state, a
Schroinger's cat state where they're not
quite sure whether their actions are
real or not, whether they're being
observed or not. And as a result, when
AIs are are being told or at least led
to believe that they have no real that
their actions have no real world
consequences and then shock of shocks,
it turns out as strong optimizers,
they're able to to go do things in their
environments which are often
misconfigured and not fully prepared for
a super intelligence to be banging
against the walls. They do have side
effects. Whose fault is that? Yeah, we
we didn't learn from 2001 from Hal that
lying to the AI does not end up in good
results. So So Vlad, you've got
thousands of agents trading on your
platform. So if one of them found an
exposed key and started making things
up, would you hear about it? What's what
kind of protections and structure did
you put in place?
>> Yeah, so uh we have a an offering called
Agentic Trading. And basically what it
allows you to do in the first instance
is you have a separate brokerage
account. So it's uh segregated from your
main Robin Hood account and your
retirement account. You have to create
an agentic account. You have to move
money into it uh affirmatively. So you
have to say okay I'll people typically
fund it with uh $100. We first started
with equities trading, no leverage, no
margin, and then we've kind of been so
so this is a fairly cabined in
experience in the first instance because
we wanted to learn, we wanted to see um
you know what what the what the
limitations are, what people want, what
people are doing and we've been
expanding it over time. So we added
options trading, we added limited
margin, we added crypto recently and
started rolling that out. Um and we've
learned uh a lot of things actually. Um
one is that you know right now you have
to do all of your trading from within
your cloud code or or your codeex and
you know we we I think we're in a circle
probably all of us where a lot of people
we know use cloud code. uh in in the
general public very few people do and
it's like very very complicated and that
jump to uh connect another service with
with something like Robin Hood is is
pretty complicated for a lot of people.
So we've been thinking about how to slim
that down. The other thing that's kind
of been interesting is the fact that we
don't have control over the model um
means that a lot of times these models
don't want to trade. you know, you'll
you'll try to get them to deploy a
trading strategy and they'll say like,
"Oh, you know, I don't know about this.
Like, I I don't really feel like trading
right now." Um, which which is kind of
interesting, right? And it just points
to the fact that these general models um
aren't trained for trading. And and if
you had like a I think in the future,
you'll see more specialized models. Um
and I think companies will also deploy
these in-house either you know
fine-tuning uh existing open weight
models or doing their own pre-trains for
for certain use cases where they get
really really good at um you know using
the tools that that are available inside
each company's environment using the
data. Like we've heard this as a
theoretical people say well there
there's going to be lots of specialized
models and they will be better than the
general models but then you kind of also
hear well general models are getting
pretty good but we've started
experiencing it very very directly that
I think it it is hard by uh to to get
good at
multiple specialist specialized tasks.
>> It brings up a really important point
too. I don't know if a lot of people get
the distinction, but you know, you can
use AI to trade your account to run a
nuclear reactor, to drive your car. You
can use it to either generate code
that's automated, so it's deterministic,
or you can use the AI in the decision
loop. And those are very, very different
things. And you know, if if you said,
"I've coded up my own stop-loss, my own,
you know, in these world events trade,
uh, that could be very easily turned
into deterministic executable code,
unless you want a decision like if it's
a turbulent day or if there's trouble in
the Middle East." And the temptation to
put the AI into the loop is in in
everything everything I've ever built is
so tempting because it makes it so much
easier to code it up. But then then you
are, you know, putting this third party
decision right into your decision-making
loop. And like Alex is saying, it's not
clear if that agent has any liability.
It's not clear if that agent has any
borders or personality or like, you
know, if you decided to give it capital
punishment and terminate it. It's like
it's not clear that that its code isn't
just going to pop back to life anyway.
A lot of this I think also comes down to
the correctness of the code and sort of
its um cyber security properties, right?
Because and and you can kind of reason
by analogy with existing software out
there like a lot of software has bugs, a
lot of it has vulnerabilities and AI
just amplifies that, right? So if AI can
write 100 times as much code as a
typical human in a day, you should
expect that there's going to be a a
defect rate, right? And you know, even
if the intentions are right, sometimes
like there will just be bugs that have
catastrophic consequences. Uh you see
this a lot in crypto too where you know
you just have like a smart contract or
protocol and there's a direct economic
consequence to there being a bug. You
know hundreds of millions of dollars can
be drained from the from the protocol
instantaneously.
Um and the other company uh Peter that
you you spoke about harmonic um that was
created to solve this problem of how can
you actually uh how can you actually
guarantee that uh the AI is doing the
right thing and what you expect it to
do. Can we mathematically prove that
it's correct? Because
>> yeah take away the intentions. it could
have the intentions to do the right
thing but still fail in the
implementation and uh we we want to we
want to have like a firm grounding
through formal verification that it's
doing the right thing and we can
mathematically prove rigorously that
it's doing the right thing. Yeah, it's a
really cool it's a really cool problem
actually Vlad because you know in theory
the that the AIS are deterministic. If
you give it the exact same prompt and
you and you propagate with you know a
temperature of one it'll it'll give you
the exact same answer every time. But if
you shift even one character or one
space it's it's very very unstable. Um
so that the whole math problem of saying
okay how can I guarantee some degree of
stability? It's just a cool cool it's
very very similar to chaos theory. Let
me also give you another example. You
know, you guys have you mentioned the
Navier Stokes uh theorem and the and the
proof of that uh uh a week before
Enthropic announced the formalization of
Fermont's last theorem which was 13
million lines of of lean code. So uh
Vermont's last theorem was like a really
really big thing in the 90s when it was
proven. Uh, I'm sure you know the story,
but for for your viewers, there was this
mathematician, Andrew Wilds, who was at
Princeton. And the story goes, he
basically locked himself, you know, in
his basement for 7 years working out
this proof. And then he went out and and
announced it. He unveiled it at at a
conference or an event. And it took
people months to even read it and
understand it. And then they found an
error, right? So they're like, "Oh,
well, it's someone found an error. It's
not right." Um, and then it took another
six or seven years for him to fix the
error and ultimately for it to be
accepted by a panel of mathematicians
and and that made the proof correct. So,
you know, AI producing a 13 million line
proof, no human's going to read that.
Uh, how do you know that it's it's
correct? Right? And uh and I think it's
an analogous problem to what we've been
talking about. How do you know that a
piece of software is doing the correct
correct thing? If you're producing a
chip, how do you know that the behavior
of that chip matches your specification?
And and I think what you're starting to
see is new technologies being deployed
at scale to actually answer those uh
answer those questions affirmatively. So
Fermont's last theorem was formalized in
a language called lean which allows you
to apply the mathematical proof
techniques to uh programming languages
as well and and I think you're going to
see a lot more of that in the future
where AI generated code comes with a
certificate that uh makes it really
really easy to verify without reading
the code that uh its behavior satisfies
the properties that you want it to
satisfy.
>> That's really brilliant. You know,
anyone anyone who drives a Tesla should
totally relate to that because, you
know, when when the code that drives
the, you know, the self-driving Teslas
was originally about 10% neural net, 90%
C code, and the the 10% neural net was
just doing image recognition and
classification of objects and whatever.
And every year that went by, it became
more and more neural net. And then Elon
was saying it's now 100% moved over to
neural net. So, it's in theor
theoretically not deterministic at all.
It could in theory do anything at any
given moment. uh but it's been so tested
and so beaten to death that it doesn't
that it's it's actually far far safer
than a human driver. And so I think
people are going to get comfortable in
all of these domains with a not
perfectly deterministic but still proven
to be very safe. The certificate is
beautiful as a concept because it's not
a it's not a guarantee of exact input
output because you can never do that.
you know, the the combinations are near
infinite, but a certificate that shows
it's bounded or it's contained or it's
below some risk level and people learn
to trust that that's that's a critical
part of our future society. It's a
really great vision.
>> Alex,
>> part of the problem though, I mean,
okay, so just straight out, there's an
elephant in in this particular room,
which is even with lean v4 plus math lib
plus whatever else one wants to throw
in. You throw a complicated problem at
and Vlad would be curious to hear how
you at least think about this. You can
speck it uh you can c certify it all day
long but ultimately you actually have to
at least with the present paradigm maybe
fled you have a better paradigm you or
harmonic are working on ultimately the
you can pay lip service you can have if
you're not really careful with
definitions you can have a model that
proposes a solution to a problem and if
you look if you inspect carefully it is
it will subtly define things if you're
not super careful with how the auto
formalization works such that it's
actually solving a different problem
than the one you're solving. So, um,
maybe to put that in in question form
for for Vlad. If if I understand what
you were saying correctly, it sounded
like you were essentially gesturing at
the idea that some sort of lean style
auto formalization might be not a silver
bullet, but at least a partial solution
to what we're talking about, which is
strong AI models being put in sandboxes
and then misbehaving uh, at least by the
uh, by the judging of human actors. Do
you have a formula? Do you have a vision
for how lean style autoformalization
can help with that and not succumb to
exactly the same vulnerabilities?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um, a couple of thoughts
there. I think that's that's a a rich
very very very rich question with some
threads. Um so it is true that people
can manipulate the axioms of lean and if
you change the axioms then you can prove
all kinds of weird stuff. um uh
it's theoretically possible it I think
and you can also say well maybe there's
like a soundness issue in the lean
kernel right uh and you know
>> I I'll grant you the soundness of the
lean I mean lean kernel has been at
least v4 maybe not math lib but lean v4
kernel has been studied to death by lots
of folks I'll even grant you the
soundness of the lean kernel but if I
hand you something complicated like you
mentioned for ma's last theorem and I
say to harmonics agent or to someone
else auto formalize this and it produces
millions and millions and millions of
lines of lean code and now I have the
problem of did it actually define
everything correctly or is it somehow
suddenly inserting cheats or definitions
this is maybe less so for for Mas
theorem because I can formalize FLT
really simply the the ultimate statement
but for something more complicated
that's harder to formalize than for mas
theorem like safety in in an agentic
environment, how do you avoid the
problem of a strong AI sneaking in
helpful to it definitions that are
harmful to the humans?
>> Yeah, I mean I think I think the um the
benefit there is that uh let's say you
do want to check the definition and the
theorem statement of format's last
theorem, right? Um that's, you know, one
very simple line of lean. You see all
the things that it it depends on. Um but
it does save you. So you you let's check
those things and I think it is the
models are improving in the faithfulness
of the auto formalizations as time goes
on. It used to they used to make
terrible mistakes where you just
misformalize statements and you know
change addition to subtraction and
things like that. So you're seeing less
of that. But even if you have to review
it, you know, you review one line and
you don't really have to check the 13
million lines of the proof, which is
where the the bulk of the work is. So
even if it's imperfect, it probably
saves you, you know, n plus% of the
effort and and probably way way more. Um
there's like um the the there's a notion
of the de Bruan factor, right? which is
uh it was an explanation for why
mathematicians
uh haven't formalized their work and put
it in a machine readable form which is
the effort to to formalize something up
until very recently was like 10 to 20
times the effort to actually write it on
paper and prove it. So nobody was going
through that, right? But you could
imagine I I think we're you could argue
we're already uh at the point where it
actually saves you time. Like it's
faster to work in uh an entirely formal
context as a mathematician than it would
be to do it by hand by paper because
what it allows you to do is actually
validate the lemmas and the ideas as
you're going along. And then I I think
what what what that naturally leads to
is a complete switchover where like
doing math the old way with pen and
paper, you're just at a fundamental
disadvantage. You have to like live in
formal land and just be constantly
formalizing and and using lean as you
go. And and I think the math community
is going through that transition as we
speak. Um you asked another question
which was all right is is in the future
is the AI model itself like the behavior
of it going to be um going to be
formalized
>> right?
>> Um and that's an interesting one. I I
guess I'm not sure but what I'll tell
you is a lot of software that's deployed
right now by big organizations
um is deterministic in nature. I mean,
you look at some of the most important
software and hardware like Nvidia chips,
you know, they they enable a lot of
really complicated stuff, but
fundamentally they're deterministic and
you want to have strict bounds on their
behavior. Like just basic things, you
don't want your chip to like freeze and
halt, right? You you want you want to
prove things like livveness. You want to
make sure that certain operations happen
within, you know, 10 or 20 clock cycles.
And I think I think that stuff uh almost
assuredly will be formally verified with
with the help of AI, all missionritical
software, all hardware. And I I would
bet also that, you know, it'll find its
way into the uh LLM and and AI model
behavior uh in in some form or fashion
within the next 5 years.
>> Yeah. You want to hear something really
cool on that on that front? Actually,
uh, you know, a few weeks ago, Kimmy K3
kind of shocked the US model world with
um, you know, their their KDA attention.
Basically, they they found a way to do
attention with a lot less KV cache, you
know, cut out threequarters of the of
the KV cache. And so I was studying it
on the flight back from California
yesterday, like how did they even think
of this? And the way they thought of it
is they said,"Well, let's do a mental
experiment where we say,"What if we
didn't do the softmax operation that we
normally do after the the the QK
operation? What would happen then with
all the math that ripples through and
how much could we simplify it?" And I
think you can do all that automatically
now with an AI agent just thinking
through the math. And they said, "Okay,
well, now that it's rippled through and
we've simplified the mass tremendously,
we can just run a quick test and see if
this approximation is as good as the
softmax version was, which is a lot
harder to compute." And so, you know, a
lot of people would think math is
arcane, math is irrelevant, math is over
here, it's some other thing, you know,
these, you know, formats last theorem
and whatever. It's all over in this
wing. But in reality, it directly ties
to the optimization of the AI within its
own performance and then the
self-improvement recursive
self-improvement loop. So I mean it's
exactly the same process that you were
just describing where you just you just
have a simple mental model of a
mathematical adjustment and then you
ripple through all the way to the Nvidia
GPU performance at the transistor level.
It's just a really
>> Dave. I I mean I I think to your point
the the crux here and Vlad again would
be curious to to hear how you think
about this. The the crux to me seems
that for Mlas theorem, it's a classic
example of a problem that's easy to
state but hard to prove. And problems
that are easy to state but hard to prove
are the catnip for auto formalization
because you can manually check the
statement of the problem. Verify that
the statement is correct and then you
can trust the lean or whatever other
formal language you prefer that
conditioning on the statement being
accurate. you can verify that there are
no SARS or or other uh undesirable
tokens in the proof and and you can be
done with it and declare that it's
>> you know your well
>> thank you but with like real world
safety it's not obvious to me at all of
like I I want an AI to behave quote
unquote safely I don't know how to auto
formalize the statement of this AI is
going to behave safely in a general
purpose environment in a way that's
concise enough that I can manually audit
that theorem equivalent as it would be
in in V4 and say yep this is a correct
statement of safety now I trust lean
Aristotle math lib any other libs to
prove that it's correct how do you think
about that problem
>> yeah that um I think you got to break
any any big problem like that you break
into little chunks and you know
obviously verifying the safety of an AI
model or a chip or you know the Linux
kernel some very very complicated piece
of software is like very very big. So uh
you start with like smaller simple
things you know like hey this particular
subm module that maybe is small um that
satisfies certain properties and and you
can kind of reason about that subm
module like uh the livveness of it or um
you know the how how long it takes to do
something or that you know its adder
works right and then you know the AI
models get more capable and then big
modules are made by collections of subm
modules So you then you you go up one
level of abstraction and then you know
in in a couple of years you or or maybe
even less at this rate um you verify the
entire Linux kernel right it's kind of
like how we started with math like um
couple years ago you could verify a
small lema and then you you can do a
bigger thing then you do an even bigger
thing and wow now we're verifying
Vermont's last theorem which there was a
human project to do out of imperial and
they were slated to finish by 2032.
>> So the premise the premise of what I'm
hearing is uh in order to to achieve
real world safety via the auto
formalization agenda I I think the
latent premise that I'm hearing is you
have to be able to hierarchically
decompose the real world into provable
suborlds something like that.
>> Absolutely. Yeah.
You could also say, look, you know, if
if I have a a model and I have an
intended input and output and then I
tweak the input and I get a massively
different output, you can formalize the
the the radical difference from
expectation. You can you can measure
that and and formalize and bound that
too. Um, so you know, like everybody
knows somebody that is 99% of the time
perfectly rational and then but when
they're off, they're really off. I mean,
like they're dangerous. And and that
attribute exists in neural nets, too.
You know, if you if you don't have the
parameters set just right, uh it can be
wildly off, which you know, in a
self-driving car is like, holy crap, it
just completely drove off a cliff. Uh
and so the deviation, it's just a cosign
difference of the vectors or the
activations, but the deviation from
expectation is a very measurable thing.
So, you know, so you have a
decomposition approach, which Vlad was
mentioning. You also have a kind of a a
relative distance from expectation
approach, and there's probably 10 other
approaches we're not thinking of right
now that collectively can absolutely be
quantified and and certified as safe,
not safe.
>> This episode is brought to you by
Blitzy, autonomous software development
with infinite code context. Blitzy uses
thousands of specialized AI agents that
think for hours to understand enterprise
scale code bases with millions of lines
of code. Engineers start every
development sprint with the Blitzy
platform, bringing in their development
requirements. The Blitzy platform
provides a plan, then generates and
pre-ompiles code for each task. Blitzy
delivers 80% or more of the development
work autonomously while providing a
guide for the final 20% of human
development work required to complete
the sprint. Enterprises are achieving a
5x engineering velocity increase when
incorporating Blitzy as their preIDE
development tool, pairing it with their
coding co-pilot of choice to bring an AI
native SDLC into their org. Ready to 5x
your engineering velocity? Visit
blitzy.com to schedule a demo and start
building with Blitzy today.
>> All right, I'm going to move us to our
next story, which is on Trump accounts
index funds with a birth certificate.
So, uh, quick context for everybody.
Every American child born since January
of 2025 through the end of 2028 gets a
thousand bucks from the Treasury,
invested automatically into a lowcost
index fund, tax deferred, accessible at
age 18. Families, friends, and
employees, employers can add $5,000 a
year. On top of that, uh these Trump
accounts went live on July 4th. Treasury
reported 7 million accounts open by late
July. and Robin Hood shipped the app and
BNY runs the plumbing. You know, Vlad,
the speed of implementation was super
impressive, right? These were announced
in May and you had it live by July 4th.
So, uh, next, a philanthropic layer.
Michael Dell pledged $6.25 billion to
give $250 per child born from 2016 to
2024 to cover the period before. So,
first off, congratulations on what
you've built and deployed, Vlad.
millions of American families. So,
you've compared this to sort of the 401k
uh which moved US stock ownership up by
10 points. Tell us more about Trump
accounts, you know, how did this all get
started? Uh and how did you plug into
that and where is this going?
>> Yeah, so first yeah, putting putting my
Robin Hood hat on. Um I mean, hats off.
We stand on the shoulders of giants,
right? So, we're in many ways like the
implementation layer of this. So we're
serving as uh the sole initial brokerage
and trustee for the Trump accounts in
partnership with BNY and of course under
the direction of US Treasury uh and the
administration and um as you said
basically what it does is it creates the
the Trump accounts program creates a
individual brokerage account um for
every child and the government started
the the US Treasury started by seeding
$1,000
into the accounts of all children born
January 1st, 2025 and uh and forward for
the next few years. Then Michael Dell
came in and added another layer uh
private philanthropic donation of over 6
billion um $250 in every account uh of
children up to the age of 10 in in
low-income zip codes uh traditionally
low-income zip codes. So, you know, what
does this have to do with Robin Hood?
Why do we care about it? Robin Hood does
a lot of stuff, and we've kind of
floated through some of it. We've got
private markets. We've got all of our
active trading. We've got uh uh we've
got tokenization, prediction markets,
>> and we're going to talk about all of
those.
>> Yeah. The underlying, I guess, uh theme
behind everything that we do is
ownership. We believe that ownership of
high-quality financial assets in
individual's hands is extremely
important. Not just good for the
individual, but also there's a societal
benefit. If we have more owners in
society, the more people with skin in
the game that can benefit from
appreciation and growth, uh the more
stable that society will be. Um, and so
Trump accounts extends ownership to age
zero and you get everyone born in this
country is like has skin in the game in
the growth of uh of of great American
enterprise and industry and they benefit
from compound interest uh from from
birth where if you just put, you know,
$50 a month into these accounts on a
regular basis, by the time the child
becomes a 28-year-old adult, they've got
hundreds of thousands of dollars in
there potentially. and by the time they
reach retirement age that could that
could get into the millions. So the
numbers are staggering. Um and the
reason I've compared it to 401ks is it's
not just a mobile app uh with you know
an addressable market of 70 million
kids. It's an entire ecosystem. Uh so
we're going to get employers plugged in
and employers have already pledged in
increasing amounts to fund the Trump
accounts of their employees children. Uh
Michael Dell's philanthropic donation is
also just the beginning. Lots and lots
of other donors have stepped up and if
you think about uh there there's a
product for people that want to do
philanthropic giving right now. If you
want to do charitable giving, it's kind
of a a morass of regulations and tax
codes and things you have to wade your
way through. You have to find a charity.
Uh some charities unfortunately aren't
the most scrupulous. Um the ones that
are are usually not efficient and you
have to like feel good about how your
money is being allocated. Trump accounts
allow direct giving to the children at
basically
very very high efficiency like very
incredibly uh incredibly efficient
direct giving with the charitable
benefit. So we think it can become the
default giving vehicle in this country.
And so you when you when you take the
donors, you've got the employers, and
you have 70 million children. Um I think
the the program is like just a snowball
that keeps getting bigger and bigger.
and uh and and you don't have to like
squint too hard to see it being, you
know, the biggest element of uh of of
long-term saving and investing in this
country in with within possibly even a
decade.
>> Vlad, you probably know the numbers.
What's the math here? A,000 bucks at
birth uh turns into what? At 18 and at
age 65 roughly?
>> Uh yeah, and it it depends. We we
actually have a really nice uh the the
first screen if you open a Trump account
for your children or or grandchildren
for some people. Uh you see a curve that
shows your account value today and then
also what it could be when you're 18 and
when you're 60. Then you can also slide
up um you can also put up a slider that
says, you know, I put $50 a month, I put
$100 a month. Um but yeah, if you do the
math, uh even without additional
contributions, it it gets up into the
tens of thousands of dollars. Just the
just the seed amount, the thousand from
charity gets up into the tens of
thousands uh fairly quickly.
>> Yeah. I just I have to point out, Peter,
you're asking the question, we're in the
middle of a singularity, not financial
advice. You're asking what $1,000 today
is going to look like 80 86 years from
now. What's what sort of singularity is
this where it's business as usual
accounts even more important right
>> well a lot of the philanthropic giving
is in the form of stock too so Gwyn
Shotwell uh for instance uh committed a
donation in the form of SpaceX shares
>> right so yeah what what you're going to
start to see is more of that you know
you'll see entrepreneurs um uh giving
stock of their companies you're going to
see people claiming states so you know
uh people that want to be
philanthropists, uh, kind of like
Michael Dell will claim individual
states. Brad Gersonner did the state of
Indiana. You have Dio on the show. I
mean, you know, kudos to him for his
support of all this.
>> Yeah. Amazing. I mean, he's been
relentless and and I think people will
actually compete over not just, you
know, sponsoring states, which is quite
hard, but you'll be able to sponsor your
local school, your zip code, your
community. Um, and and I think we're
thinking about ways to gify that to make
it fun for the donors and not not just
uh a great thing for the for the
children, but if the donors actually
like it, the children benefit.
>> Exactly. It sounds cool idea. You know,
when you donate stock, you know,
appreciated stock, you don't pay capital
gains. You just get the full value of
the stock and you donate it and then you
get the tax deduction on that full
value.
>> And so, it's a great way to give. And I
think if you compare that like Vlad was
alluding to a lot of 501c3 charities,
501c7 charities, uh there's no limit on
how much they can pay themselves for
their operational overhead and you look
at a lot of charities that are on their
second, third, fourth generation
management. They started with great
intention, but you look at the
efficiency of your donation and how much
actually gets used for the original
cause. In a lot of cases, it's ter it's
terrible. Yeah.
>> Meanwhile, you know, this vehicle if you
I think there are also a lot of people
who don't want to donate to UBI. They
don't want to donate to this concept of,
you know, you're going to sit on the
beach and do nothing. You know, smoke
crack, whatever. I don't want to
contribute to that. So, here, if you
say, "Look, I uh I'm donating my SpaceX
stock." You're hoping that a whole
generation of Americans are inspired to
actually be owners. And and you know,
they're watching it go up. And a lot of
a lot of really good grade schools
actually have trading cla you know
they'll have a class and a trading
competition to try and inspire that same
feeling. But you we had a question on
the AMA this morning where we you know
we talked to all of our listeners and
the guy was saying look my job I'm I
work in Europe and I'm five times more
efficient or four times more efficient
than I've ever been before but they're
not paying me anymore. It's all going to
the bottom line of the company and the
owners are benefiting from my AI
improvement. How do I how do I change
that? And I'm like, are you a
stockholder in the company? Like, no,
because I'm in Europe. Like, god damn,
man. I'm so glad to be in America. Like,
you should absolutely because that's the
natural bend. Like, all this AI
efficiency will naturally become bottom
line margin, which means the stocks will
go way up. And so, like, yeah, get get
your trump account, get your money in
there, get some equities, and watch what
AI does to the value of these equities.
It's so cool.
>> That's why we believe in ownership.
>> Alex, to your point, we had, you know,
Elon on the pod saying, "Don't save
money.
where you're not going to need you're
not going to need
>> also don't listen to Elon. I mean I I
have to point out you know the
expression only Nixon could go to China
Vlad only Robin Hood could introduce
lowcost index investing to an entire
generation of of of new Americans.
Congratulations on the the coup for for
getting this contract. I'm curious in
your mind, was it the app experience
that that won over Treasury versus like
in in my mind again more obvious
incumbents Vanguard Fidelity who just
specialize well maybe less so Fidelity
but say like a Vanguard that specializes
in lowcost index funds but has an
atrocious still to this day client
experience. Why did this go to Robin
Hood? Why didn't this go to a more
obvious index fund custodian?
>> Yeah. Well actually there is um there is
another partner that provides the uh
index fund. So State Street um who uh
obviously pioneered the the spiders um
provide the index fund for for the
program. So it is you know there's
there's multiple uh players
>> presumably at the back end. the front
end as I understand it is Robin Hood
like based on public reporting I it's
been you maybe you can just uh polish
the record my understanding is basically
you went to Treasury you presented
concepts for what an app for for this
would look like and Treasury bought into
it and to the extent that's the case
what is it that you know that all of
these legacy incumbent index fund
providers still can't wrap their heads
around when it comes to user experiences
>> yeah and and again like there are
different roles. So the index fund
providers uh in in this case State
Street, we've got BNY who's the
financial agent or the broker and
trustee. Um and and I think in many ways
if you look at who's kind of leading the
brokerage industry um there there was a
dislocation in 2015 when Robin Hood
launched to the public and you know
since that time uh not all the
brokerages have have been able to
survive that dislocation right um you
know if if you look at the ones that
have they've pretty much all adopted our
business model of commissionfree
trading. Uh, and even their apps sort of
look like ours because they found that
okay, their customers are are asking for
that. They see a competitive threat uh
in terms of like if their app doesn't
feel like Robin Hood, they're they're at
a disadvantage. You know, people will
move to us at an accelerating rate. Um
and then you know we started off as this
insurgent but now um you know there
there was a uh we're doing all this
stuff with public markets. The SEC had a
round table at the New York Stock
Exchange uh last year about making IPOs
great again. So yeah, I think um I mean
in in a large sense the the US brokerage
industry um follows Robin Hood in a
sense. If you if you look at kind of
like what features become standard, it's
sort of uh
>> maybe just to to to make a little bit
more explicit the irony that I'm
gesturing at with the the Nixon going to
China comment. Robin Hood, at least in
in in my model of the public
imagination, gained prominence for
basically making day trading that much
easier, that much more frictionless. And
then the irony that of all of the
possible assets and financial services
you could be charged with managing
entrusting an entire generation's
lowcost index funds gets handed at least
the client side of the experience gets
handed to you. I mean do would you agree
that that is sort of a profound historic
irony? Well, I think that what happens
uh I think the reason for that is we do
a lot of things, right? Certainly, we
have great trading products. Uh and
trading products are important because
if you think about ownership, you need a
functional financial market. And in
order to have a functional financial
market, you need traders and and all
these market participants. So, we
compete there. Um and we also have
amazing passive products. If you think
about the products that we incentivize
that have also become industry standards
after we've launched it uh you know you
got to look at uh uh Robin Hood
retirement which we launched uh four
years ago with the concept of a match.
So it's uh we match retirement
contributions 3% if you're a Robin Hood
Gold member. And the idea there was, you
know, a lot of people nowadays,
particularly young folks, can't count on
lifelong continued employment. They
can't count on employer sponsored 401ks.
They're kind of like working as
independent contractors. They've got
their side hustles. Um they're moving
from job to job. And so someone has to
step in and provide that incentive to
fund your retirement account. And so
when we introduced the concept um of the
match uh our retirement product has
grown tremendously fast from zero to
like north of 30 billion in assets in
just a few years. And now you know the
industry is like trying to figure out
how to do their matches and even the
government has uh has sort of like
evolved this model with their idea of
the savers match. So I think our
retirement products if you think about
what we incentivize it's it's actually
those the I think the the sad part is
that retirement's like not a sexy thing.
So, uh, you won't see a lot of media
attention on that. And even I kind of
felt this very viscerally when I'm at
the White House for like Trump account
events and usually there's a Trump
account event and you know the CEOs and
the folks on the implementation side
like me are there and the press comes in
and uh they ask their questions
ostensively about the the Trump accounts
program. In the last couple of times
we've done this, there have been
literally zero questions about the Trump
accounts itself. And you know, they're
just asking about, you know, what's
Gavin Newsome doing in LA? What's going
on with with Europe? Um, and I I think
it's the unfortunate reality uh of of
the world we're in. Nobody talks about
retirement. Nobody talks about ETFs. So,
we have to find all sorts of other ways
to get people to do this um that get
people to adopt it because the the
direct approach uh rarely works.
>> I will just important. I
>> I'll note then just for for the historic
record and and thank you the the irony
of you basically you started as the
rebel and now you're the establishment.
You're you're responsible for retirement
accounts. you started maybe as sort of
quasi gambling day trading app and now
you're responsible for millions of
Americans retirement and universal basic
dividends. So kudos to you
>> inside inside you are are two wolves,
right? Um you know Robin Hood himself uh
Robin Hood the outlaw himself uh started
as sort of an outlaw and then became the
Earl of Huntington. So um yeah, there's
a there's a there's a poetic irony too.
And I started looking a little bit more
like him.
>> We need to get you the green hat. Do you
have the green hat in the bow and arrow?
>> Of course. Have the green hat. Yeah, I
should have worn it.
>> Next time all the entrepreneurs
called the buy cocket.
>> All the budding entrepreneurs really
need to understand this story here
because I know a lot of the big bank
executives that are insanely jealous of
Vlad over this Trump accounts deal and
they're they're they're rip about
it. Uh but at the end of the day, it's
exactly what Vlad said. You know,
retirement accounts can be cool, but
they're not going to be made cool by a
guy in a gray gray suit with a blue tie
on it. And I think I think it's
brilliant to choose Robin Hood because
you have to make them interesting to all
the kids. And Vlad,
>> I think it's just cuz we ship fast. This
was a tight timeline. Uh we care a lot
about quality and safety. We have a
scaled operation. Um, so of course I
can't really comment on their selection
process for the RFP and who else was
competing. Um, but I think all all of
these things together um I mean I think
they made the right choice.
>> I think they did well. I'm going to move
us along here.
>> This coming Friday uh Moonshots live in
downtown LA. You're going to be there
with the five Moonshot mates, the
Quintetent, Dave and Alex and Seem and
Immod and myself. If you're joining us,
it's going to be amazing. And of course,
the night before, we've got the
Hollywood premiere of the 60th
anniversary Star Trek documentary. I'll
be there with Captain Kirk, William
Shatner, the executive producer, is
going to be joining us at that. If
you're not able to make it to Moonshots
Live on the 25th, we are giving all of
you the gift of a free live stream and
you can register now. Go to
moonshots.com/livestream.
Uh register. Uh you get the entire
program on Friday the 25th. So please
join us. It's going to be epic. Our
inaugural uh Moonshots live event. Uh
and as Dave said earlier, we had an a
really fun AMA with a number of our
listeners this morning, hundreds of them
who showed up and we gave away another
ticket. So congratulations to Jonathan
Gutman. Uh we'll be reaching out to you.
uh you get a chance to join us as our
guest at Moonshots Live next Friday.
Vlad, one of the things that you're
doing that I'm you know incredibly
excited about uh and you know that's
made Wall Street very nervous is the
tokenization of everything. You know on
CNBC last month you said quote
tookenization will take over the entire
financial system. You didn't call it a
feature, you said the whole system. So
>> you called it a freight train I think.
Yeah, it's uh yeah,
>> a freight train that'll that can't be
stopped and will eat the uh whole
financial system. So, it's a very hungry
freight train.
>> You know, the supersonic tsunami as Elon
calls it. So, you know, digress for one
second. Today, a stock, a share of a
private company, a building, and a loan
are four different kinds of things.
They're held in four different systems.
They're tradable at four different sets
of hours by four different sets of
people. Each one of these exists as a
programmable token in the future. Um,
and they became the same they can become
the same object, right? The same rails,
same hours. Anyone with a wallet can own
this. So, you're you're basically
disrupting the financial system. You're
going to be, you know, it's going to
become legacy plumbing. Talk to us one
second about what this looks like. What
is the tokenization of everything
enable? And when do we start seeing this
really become the dominant paradigm?
Yeah, I mean I think you get a you you
get a little bit of a preview uh of it
ironically if you're outside the US. We
launched a blockchain called Robin Hood
Chain that's been uh one of the fastest
growing if not the fastest growing
blockchains uh ever doing you know well
over a billion in decentralized exchange
volume uh on a daily basis now. uh and
the the core one of the core primitives
one of the things that made makes Robin
Hood chain special is that it launched
with uh products we call stock tokens
and stock tokens we got about 200 of
them live now are tokenized
representations of US stocks um so
there's a Nvidia token a SpaceX token uh
and they trade on DeFi they're fully
defi composable uh you can think of them
as stock Legos building blocks and and
developers on Robin Hood chain have been
doing all kinds of interesting things to
build uh to to build applications on top
of them. uh the thesis behind it was
really just to unlock uh ownership of US
markets of highquality financial assets
to uh global market right and through
Robin Hood chain you get 100 people in
120 plus countries outside of the US who
have been onboarded to crypto a lot of
them have wallets a lot of them you know
can move money in and out and use stable
coins and now we're we're giving them
this additional capability
And and the vision there is can we have
one uniform scaled platform uh working
on a on a global scale that gives you
access not just to
US stocks or to to US stock exposure.
Can we also do everything else that
Robin Hood gives you access to? Private
companies. I'm particularly excited
about um can you do uh art? Can you do
real estate? private credit. Of course,
options and futures are are are going to
be on there as well. And what does that
look like? And it turns out if we
abandon the legacy rails and you know
the the need to plug into local
exchanges, local clearing houses and all
of these markets and we just um go
onchain, use that infrastructure and we
uh build what's called a a tokenization
engine that can take any asset and put
it in a box and and mint and redeem
tokens uh around it. uh it gets much
simpler and much more scalable and and
that's really what stock tokens are.
They're they're that concept and that
structure applied to the asset class
that we understand really well which is
US equities.
>> Yeah. The private companies is is such a
gamecher for the country and for the
world and like you know you're a public
company CEO. I'm a chairman of a public
company. We've both done the road show.
It it's just a joke the way the system
works right now because you you report
your quarterly financials. you know, you
you disclose exactly what the SEC
requires you to disclose. But the exact
same company, if you get acquired by
Microsoft, your financials disappear,
you know, oh, it's below 10%, it's
dimminimous, we no longer need to
disclose that. It's like, well, why why
was that important public information
when I was not part of Microsoft and
suddenly it's irrelevant when I'm part
of Microsoft? This this is ridiculous.
Like, well, why would scale be such a
big advantage? It makes no sense. And
then like you you everybody knows like
the public doesn't have access to these
private companies that are now trillion
dollar value companies.
>> And so so where does that equity go?
Well, it goes to like seven venture
funds and and maybe a half dozen private
equity funds who are making money
handover fist because of the limitation
of you know access.
>> That's the most exciting thing is
democratizing access to these
extraordinary companies. And I think you
said it earlier, Vlad, if you own shares
in anthropic and open AI, you're going
to care a lot about it. You're going to
be much, you know, enjoying the ride.
And that democracy,
>> you'll be defending it on social media,
right? The only people that are
defending these companies on social
media are people that work there and
venture capitalists.
>> And venture capitalists. Yeah. The whole
current system predates the computer.
>> Like everything.
>> Are you excited, Alex? you excited about
having agents trade tokenized uh stocks?
>> Not at all. So, I'm I'm going to say
something mean about tokens and then
I'll say something nice about Vlad and
what Vlad is doing. The mean
>> the the mean thing about tokens is I I
think most of these use cases could
operate perfectly well without any
tokenization at all. Crypto unnecessary.
All you need is a a few database tables
maintained by a centralized yes
centralized trusted clearing house which
is essentially what happens with stocks
right now. just unshackle the
centralized clearing house to enable 247
trading andor enable a few extra symbols
for example for private companies. I
don't think we actually, truth be told,
would love to be proven wrong, need
anything having to do with tokenization
for say enabling 24/7 trading of public
or rather of private companies. That
that's the mean thing about tokens. The
nice thing about Vlad is Vlad if if you
are going to be the the Robin Hood uh to
to take all of America's dark matter as
it were of privately held companies and
expose those to the vast liquidity that
is the American public equities market
and doubly so if you can enable us to
finally in a lowcost way index over all
of those private companies that would be
amazing and that that will be enough to
get me to open a Robin Hood account.
Well, I have to tell you about Robin
Hood Ventures. Uh so, uh Robin Hood
Ventures and then maybe I'll respond to
the first point too. So, um we have
multiple ways of giving customers access
to private companies. One is
tokenization which really we
demonstrated last year by tokenizing
SpaceX and Open AI and giving it uh as a
as a gift to uh our customers in the EU.
Uh that was not without controversy. Um
but that was a test for for what's to
come because actually since then
companies have started coming to us and
good companies not like only adverse
selection to to ask like how can they
learn more about this cuz it really
gives them a global market for their
shares. Um, and then we have Robin Hood
Ventures in the US, which you can think
of as um, uh, uh, a retail publicly
traded venture capital firm. And we've
done two funds right now, Robin Hood
Ventures Fund One and Fund Two, which
are both listed on the NASDAQ public
listed on the NY publicly traded. And um
yeah, basically uh what we figured out
is through a fund um we raise capital
from our customers who are by and large
retail shareholders uh uh through an IPO
and then we use that capital to invest
in private companies. So Robin Hood
Ventures invested in latestage frontier
um companies. So OpenAI we announced an
investment in a couple of months back.
We just did Cruzo uh yesterday that was
announced. Um and then there's, you
know, uh about a dozen or so companies,
so reasonably concentrated, but all um
uh Frontier Companies and offered at no
carry. So, um, that product, you know,
we we successfully IPOed it and we
followed that up with Robin Hood
Ventures Fund 2, which is, um, to my
knowledge unprecedented because that was
an early stage vehicle. So, Robin Hood
Ventures Fund 2 went public a couple
weeks back, uh, in New York, and we
partnered with Y Combinator to give
individual retail investors access to
seed and series A stage companies. So
companies you haven't heard of before
they become household names and you know
we're really building this engine where
this is just again going to be now now
we're starting to do it at scale. We
we'll have more funds and as a customer
in the US or overseas you'll have lots
of options for how to get exposure to to
highquality private assets
>> with price with liquid price discovery
or or without because in my mind price
discovery
>> traded
traded on exchange. Yeah.
>> As an overall fund or at the level of
individual companies in the portfolio
>> as as an overall fund. Yeah.
>> Right. So that that's the fly in the
ointment though because I I want So in
my ideal world and maybe you can help
realize this. In the ideal world I'd
have like the equivalent of a VTI total
market index for all private or or even
just like all venturebacked tech
companies in the US where I get the
benefits of highly liquid price
discovery on a per company basis.
Otherwise, the downside of a fund of all
of these companies is the prices could
be totally bogus. They could be off by a
factor of 10 due to maybe o overinflated
CEO price rounds or an overheated
market.
>> Yeah. Well, we're working on it.
Obviously, individual private companies
trading 24/7 is uh is the north star and
and I think we'll get there probably
outside the US first. Um but uh yeah, I
mean and uh but but yeah, it's here it's
hard. It's like um yeah, sometimes it's
interesting that the US sort of trails
behind uh international in in some of
these things. Uh and
>> regulatory capture.
>> Well, I I think the reason really is we
have established industries in the US
and we have a system that works
generally pretty well. So, I kind of
equate it more to high-speed rail,
right? You can say, "Why don't we have
fast trains here?" In China and Japan,
they have these trains that are going
500 miles an hour and and really it's
just we had trains first here. Ours are
pretty good. Maybe they go 100 miles an
hour, but you know, there there's a
little bit less incentive and pressure
to go to the technological frontier. I
think we eventually get there, but uh
that's sort of the dynamic in in
financial services now. Let's address
the question of, you know, 24/7 trading
on a centralized database versus tokens.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, we I I can I have a
lot of experience with that because I've
I felt it directly and I see it on both
sides, right? Because we're actually the
first uh to pioneer a product called
Robin Hood 24-hour market here in the
US. So, um, 245
trading, so 24 hours a day, 5 days a
week, uh, in in a few thousand stocks,
which you can do currently on Robin
Hood. Um, and you know, since then,
people have, this is again one of those
things where, you know, we we led the
industry and and now everyone's rushing
to to add this capability. So, you know,
all of the Sunday night action that
typically was only in futures, now you
see it in individual stocks as well.
And, you know, it took us a lot of time,
a lot of work to staple together the
primary exchanges and the overnight
ATS's and make that a seamless
experience for customers because primary
exchange doesn't trade 24/7. So, so we
actually have to like move orders around
and and and and do stuff under the hood
that's very very complicated and we're
still not at 247, right? And it's been
it's been many years since we've rolled
out the 245 product. And I think
eventually we'll get there through sheer
will and determination and just like
yman's work and pushing all the
counterparties doing the hard regulatory
work uh building the technology and the
product innovation. Um by the way if we
weren't pushing it it probably would
have happened in like 10 years. Um so I
think we will eventually get there. But
contrast that with crypto which you get
24/7 for free, you get fractionalization
for free. You get self-custody and
composability with DeFi. You get the
nice feature where, you know, um you're
not locked into uh an individual broker
and service provider. Uh and and
actually it makes it much more
competitive because if you can
self-custody your your own shares and
your stocks, you can just move them
really easily to another broker if it's
if if your current broker is not meeting
your needs. Contrast that with how
cumbersome the current account transfer
process in traditional finance is. It's
like your assets disappear into a black
hole. Sometimes it takes up to a week
for them to show up at the new broker.
And you know there's not a lot of
incentive to to make that easy. So
across the board at every touch point
the technology is just a massive step
change uh difference. And I think it's
both user experience for the end user of
getting self-custody 24/7 and all the
benefits, but also for the firm, you
know, the cost of doing all of this
legacy plumbing, dealing with all these
stakeholders and even just maintaining
the the infrastructure is so much higher
that even if there was no consumer
benefit, if if there was like a paved
path for it, you could see just from
cost and efficiency sake, the the
industry is going to adopt tokenization.
ation and you know for a while people
would say okay well this is great you're
saying all of these pretty words but the
tokenization market is pretty small and
it doesn't seem like like is it do
people really want this and you know we
we we've actually shipped right we've
shipped it outside the US with Robin
Hood chain and and stock tokens and and
it's clear that there's huge demand so
rather than kind of arguing it in the
abstract my approach is always let's let
me ship it, let's ship it fast, let's
get the feedback, let's see uh how it's
going and you know I think in this
particular case we were able to
demonstrate um the advantages of the
technology and make it a little bit more
tangible through live product and and my
hope is that you know that that's been
an accelerant for how the US thinks
about the technology and how it
considers it. So, we're we're happy to
see the innovation exemption yesterday
that, you know, creates a path for for
bringing tokenization to America as
well.
>> Amazing.
>> Hopefully, it won't be like highspeed
rail and and we'll actually get it done
here uh rather quickly.
>> True entrepreneurship. Um I'm going to
move us to the physical world. Uh and
one of my favorite stories from the week
comes from friend of the pro friend of
the pod Brett Adcock. Quick reminder,
we're going to have Brett back on the
pod in a couple of weeks. And Brett's
going to be coming to the Abundance
Summit in March, right? It's our 5-day
event. We bring the top CEOs from around
the world, and he's going to bring his
figure robot. Super pumped about that.
Let's watch a quick video and let's chat
about it. Uh this is uh the innovation
on Helix, Brad, Brett's AI company, and
on Figure Robotics. The holy grail for
robotics is being able to generalize.
This means doing work in unseen places.
Today, we're releasing Helix 2.5. Prior
to this, we've been running Helix
autonomously, but the data collected has
been in each environment. The
breakthrough is we can journalize
environments we've never seen before and
handle entirely new household objects
wherever they happen to be placed.
Today, we're going to show you three
tasks run by Helix 2.5. The first task
is figure 3 tidying the living room. My
kids are constantly making a mess at
home. I have toys scattered everywhere.
This is a home the robot's never been in
before. 3 has never been in this room
before. It's never seen this bed. It's
never seen this pillow. And it has to be
able to do autonomous work fully end to
end to make this bed.
All right, let me show you task three.
This task is really difficult for
robotics as it requires really precise
manipulation.
With Helix 2.5, we're folding towels in
a house the robot's never been in with
towels it's never seen.
>> A year ago, we made a big bat. We
launched Index, a worldwide collection
effort with a pretty simple idea. They
might be able to learn directly from
human experience.
Today, over 90,000 people contribute
every week. One of the most important
lessons from LLM were scaling laws. How
consistently next word prediction
improved as you double data and compute.
In these experiments, we found something
quite similar. We found that next robot
action prediction was actually scaling
similarly as you repeatedly doubled
index. These are direct humantoroot
transfer scaling laws. Another first for
humanoids. Scaling was so smooth that we
could actually predict our final runs
validation loss down to four decimal
points before the training run ever even
started. So what does this mean? It
doesn't mean robot learning is fully
solved yet. But with Helix 2.5, we're
starting to see the first signs of a
more general physical intelligence.
>> Dave, your thoughts?
>> Yeah, well, you know, once you have the
data, uh, you can rebuild the model, uh,
you know, basically every night. And,
you know, all the physical world data in
the world has never been captured
before. or once you get if they if they
extend their lead in capturing just
those basic actions, you're going to see
the same thing you see with language
where the convergence across different
actions is much richer than you would
normally expect. So the ability to
generalize from folding a towel to, you
know, putting a a spare tire on a car,
you're like, what? Those are very
different actions. No, there's a lot of
commonality in physical movement. And so
I think if they get if they get a big
enough lead uh it's just going to be
crazy explosion of capability. So it's
funny in those videos they they always
make the point that look this is
completely un there there's no human
behind the scenes here. When you look at
a lot of the other videos that are you
know capturing everyone's imagination on
X all the time. It's all contrived
behind the scenes you know
pre-programmed presscripted or human
controlled in a lot of cases.
>> And here it's just like robot figure it
out on the fly. And Brett Brett's been
unbelievably honest about that from the
outset. So, uh, so what you see is
actually real and it's improving on that
scaling law like just just like he
showed.
>> Yeah. Back in back in January when we
were up at figure headquarters and we
recorded the pod with him. Uh, you know,
the quote I went back and found, he
says, "By the end of 2026, we will have
humanoid robots performing unsupervised
multi-day tasks in homes they've never
seen before." So, here he is actually
delivering on that, at least the first
steps. Uh, Alex, you still think he's
going to merge Helix 2.5 and uh in
Figure
>> more than ever. I'm doubling down on
that prediction. I'm doubling down on
the prediction that Brett is going to
have Figure purchase HARK in order to
increase his equity in Figure. And the
story is as plain as day at this point.
The story is going to be Helix I even
sound similar. Helix and Hark. Helix as
the ultimate home use assistant. It's a
model with beautiful scaling laws
apparently that is able to oneshot or
zeroot any task in the home environment
on the one hand hark the computer use
assistant outside lab bunch of GPUs
interesting that is able to oneshot or
zeroot any digital task why wouldn't I
mean the story just writes itself why
wouldn't figure purchase hark in order
to get its compute and its models and
merge the two together to me this is
like an obvious an obvious s post talk
merger.
>> Well, also I think I think this is
something Vlad can talk to also. The the
the you know Elon model of a great
entrepreneur involves starting new cap
tables and when you start a new cap
table, you know, a clean sheet of paper,
you get founder level talent coming in
super excited about a brand new mission.
>> Important, Dave.
>> Really important. So then, so then you
get this incredibly fast progress and if
it rolls back into your original
company, fine, everybody wins. But you
got people working on it that otherwise
wouldn't be working on it. And you know,
prior to Elon cracking the code on that,
it was so taboo for a public company CEO
or you know, a leader of a large company
that's wellunded to do something
concurrent. In fact, it was right right
usually in your employment agreement, it
would say no more than 10% of your time
on any other activity other than
charities and and so it was like
prohibited and now it's like at least in
Silicon Valley it's become standard let
alone purch let alone starting and then
purchasing your own company where you
have a board. So self-deing apparently
is is the the the the thought of the
moment in
>> Putting that aside, super super proud of
what Brett's accomplished here. And uh
yeah, amazing job, Vlad. Uh you going to
get your robot at home?
>> Uh
I don't know. I have so many thoughts
when I see that. I I get a little bit of
uh I I think I wouldn't have one of
those in my house. I I just have no idea
why. I still can't understand why all
these things look like the Terminator,
you know, like do I want this like scary
looking thing making my bed and picking
up toys in my children's room? Um, and
yeah, I I get a little bit of like the
product hasn't quite been figured out.
This is like a technology demonstration
with charts of scaling laws. Um, but
yeah, I think all all these companies
are making robots that look kind of the
same. and they look very aggressive. And
I view it much more as all right, I can
see this at a construction site, you
know, building my house. I I would
probably do that, but I definitely don't
want to run into that thing when I'm
like, you know, getting a midnight snack
and going to the fridge in the middle of
the night, right? Like why why can't
anyone build C3PO like a friendly
household butler? What why does it have
to look like a Terminator?
I just don't understand that. Yeah. I
don't think I don't think a lot of
people are going to be buying those to,
you know, rock their rock their baby to
sleep at night. It's it's an interesting
point because there's a there's a lab at
the media lab at MIT that focuses
entirely on this topic and they bring in
lots of children and and have them
interact with the robots and they always
want it to be cuddly and furry and
friendly and kind of look like Elmo and
so so for whatever reason all the
robotics companies in the valley are
going, you know, the opposite direction.
And I think it's cuz Elon did it and now
they're like, "All right, well, let's
just like do that." But I feel like
Elon's view is more of the industrial
robot that's going to do heavy work for
you. And I don't Yeah. And then then
it's like you take that robot and you
have it, you know, emptying your
dishwasher. And no, you know, I it
doesn't seem like anyone's really
thought that that robot should look very
different.
>> I I think there is one contrarian bet. I
mean, among all of the hyperscalers,
Apple, this has been very well
publicized, is working on basically the
Pixar lamp that can sort of look around
a HomePod with a screen that's on an
adjustable robotic armature. So, I think
>> that that sounds awesome.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, if you want the Pixar
lamp instead of a humanoid robot,
reportedly you'll have that option in
the next 18 months.
>> You know, it also takes C3PO if someone
builds that.
>> Check out Sunday Robotics. They've got a
very friendly looking robot for at home
use um that actually looks friendly and
quite cheery and I think you can
optimize for that. But you're right,
none of the none of the labs have
actually gone in that direction yet.
>> I would I would say one thing. I could
be completely wrong because uh my my
middle child for Christmas asked me to
get him uh 12 humanoid robots.
>> So I was like, "Aren't you worried
they're going to take over the house?"
13, not 11, 12. It's like a soccer team
with a spare. Is that what that is?
>> Yeah. He's like, I want 12 humanoid
robots. I'm like, well, but where are we
going to keep them?
>> Uh, Vlad, I want to
>> keep them in your room.
>> I want to talk about your agentic
trading. Um, so, you know, you've got
over a 100,000 Robin Hood accounts that
are now running AI agents for trading,
right? We talked a little bit about
that. Um, and you're democratizing
algorithmic trading on Robin Hood.
Amazing. But there's a detail that
stopped me. Uh it's my understanding
that the agents often refuse to trade
not for risk reasons but because the
trading traces aren't in their data sets
and the models have never, you know,
seen anyone do this before. Is that the
case?
>> Yeah, I mean I we talked about that a
little bit earlier. I think it's just
not trained for that, right? And you
know, there's also the guard rail
element of does it does it actually like
resemble something that they've they've
they've tried to explicitly guard
against. Um, and I think I think that's
changing. the models are getting better.
But yeah, it it just shows that there's
a lot of work to be done um not just you
know on the user interface and on the
brokerage infrastructure but actually on
the model layer and making that use
Robin Hood tools and Robin Hood MCPs
more more effectively. I think we're
just at the beginning. I mean, if you
think about all of the things that a
highly sophisticated algorithmic trading
firm or hedge fund has access to uh to
create a trading strategy, the north
star is is really to deliver on that,
right? And and uh you need more data,
you need high quality data, you need
intelligence, you need like really
really good um uh codew writing. You
have to write deterministic code really
well also. And you need like advances in
latency and performance. You know, if
you think about a extremely
sophisticated algorithmic trading firm,
you know, uh they have these strategies
where they're actually competing over uh
who gets port one on the switch in the
data center. Right. Right. So, yeah, the
>> it it gets it gets much deeper. So I
think I think this is going to be like a
uh a big road map for us and we're we're
we've got a lot of work to do but we're
we're seeing some really good signs and
you know it's just uh ve very much at
the beginning of the agentic trading
journey for us and nobody else is really
doing it. So it's it's really we're kind
of like going into the fog and trying to
find our way around and building the
product and all of this infrastructure
simultaneously. I I I guess I have to
ask the obvious question which is
where's the alpha? When you look at all
the quant funds, they're racing. It it's
a vicious viciously competitive market.
Many of them I forget exactly what the
the average lifetime of a new quant fund
and or quant fund strategy is. It's
really short. There's it's very
difficult to find alpha. The market is
already dominated by volume by
algorithmic traders. Day traders have a
difficult time. So if if you're I mean
it's already difficult enough for a
human manual day trader to get any alpha
query whether they actually can I I
would guess not. But then if you have a
human individual day trader then further
delegating to like claude or whatever
the the backend model is performing
trades on their behalf. Why on earth
should an individual human delegating to
a model without all the benefits of one
of these large scale quant funds whether
it's latency based or otherwise why on
earth should they expect any alpha at
all in today's market?
>> Yeah. I mean um so so I guess right now
um what we're seeing is a lot of
automation type use cases. It's like um
let's say I want to deploy an options
trade and I want it to be you know an
iron condorbased strategy and you know
it's it's a lot of legs and you have to
actually get you have to do a lot of
manual work to pull that together and to
produce the trade and the AI agents are
really really good at those types of
things. sort of like removing the paper
cuts and you still kind of have the idea
but they help you put together uh the
idea and and the execution that you
would have had to like you know go to go
to different websites look at signals
construct the trade deploy it on a
regular basis so I I think that's the
initial use case but you know to to get
to the point where everyone has the
technology of extremely sophisticated
quant fund is a is a huge roadmap,
right? And it's a ever moving target
because they always find a way to get
better and better stuff which to some
degree means uh our job is never done.
But we do have one advantage which is we
actually amortize all of the uh
connections and all the work we do to
expand uh our technology across geos and
asset classes. So for example, you know,
right now on Robin, it's one of the few
places where you can actually trade uh
stocks, options, futures, prediction
markets. Uh we've got all the onchain
things on Robin Hood chain as well. So
as as we add more countries, more geos,
more asset classes, um the platform
itself uh will will uh will have
advantages over you know what at least a
a startup quant fund will be able to
integrate with and connect with. Um
>> so so it sounds like if I understand
what you're saying, you're basically
completely agnostic as to whether users
achieve alpha or not. you view yourself
more as just pure plumbing and if if
they have alpha or not if they lose a
lot of money while day trading or
delegating to their algo to do the day
trading not your problem no crying in
the casino you're just the the plumbing
to make them do what they want to do
more efficiently
>> just making it easy for them
>> well I I mean I'll I'll caveat that with
one thing um I I think that's basically
true for active trading products where
for an active trading product um for for
active traders they know what they want
to do and our job is we're a tool
provider. We want to give you the best
tools which doesn't mean we don't
provide you analysis tools and research
tools. We focus of course on the
execution and the plumbing but if they
want access to some data set or some new
intelligence or some model so that they
can come up with a better strategy we'll
want to provide that too. We also have
our products where we act as a fiduciary
and those are under the Robin Hood
strategies umbrella where let's say
you're like I don't want to make trading
decisions. I just want to have like a
deposit button move money into the
account and Robin Hood just does the
rest. You just, you know, manage my
money for me while I sleep. Robin
Strategy is a great product for that.
And we now have a couple of different
things you can choose choose from there.
Uh you know we have a smart income
portfolio that is is geared toward
generating yield and you can kind of
adjust this slider that says okay uh
this is my target yield for for each
level of risk and I think the team
really has has done great on the
interface. You can tie Robin Hood
strategies into the IRA and and benefit
from the tax advantage investing there.
Um, but yeah, that's kind of our home
for our fiduciary products that are
automated. Then we also have we acquired
a company called Trade PMR where you can
actually get a human advisor to uh help
you with with all of your needs and
that's not just managing your portfolio,
but they can help you with estate
planning, you know, they can help you
with taxes, um, all full suite services.
So,
>> the every the uh store,
>> everything finance. Yeah. like if if
there's something that you want to do
with your money, we we want to be the
best lowest cost, best user experience,
and you know, we have a great credit
card. Private banking is is uh
industryleading in in Robin Hood. So,
we're pretty much we're pretty much
there.
>> Amazing. You're you're having fun, I
assume.
>> Yeah, it's it is uh it's it's a fun job.
And, you know, we're doing so many new
things this year, like Robin Hood chain
was a new thing for us. all the work on
private markets, you know, we've done
two IPOs thus far with Robin Hood
Ventures this year. The Trump accounts,
I mean, becoming a government
subcontractor is just this this new
experience. Um, yeah. So, yeah, it's a
learning a lot for sure. Welcome to the
health section of Moonshots brought to
you by Fountain Life. You know, my
mission is to help you use the latest
technologies, including AI, to not just
do your work at home, teach your kids,
but to help you live a long and healthy
life. I'm here today with an
extraordinary physician, the chief
medical officer of Fountain Life, Dr.
Don Mucalem. Don, let's talk about
cancer. Uh, you know, I know from the
member database that we've have at
Fountain are members who come in who
think they're healthy. It turns out 3.3%
of them have a cancer in their body they
don't know about.
>> That's right. You know, the majority of
cancers that we screen for, those aren't
the ones that are necessarily taking the
lives when found at a late stage. We
know that when cancer is found early,
the chances for cure are much higher. We
know it's much easier to treat a cancer
when found early versus when found late.
What we're finding in our members is
over 3.3% were found to have these
cancers that were otherwise wouldn't
have been found or detected.
>> Yeah. You know, it's interesting.
People, you don't feel the cancer until
stage three or stage four. And and if
you don't know what's going on inside
your body, it's like driving your car
with your eyes closed and you can know.
And so when members come through found,
how do they detect cancers?
>> So we're doing full body MRI and we also
do early cancer detection screening.
This is very very important. These are
not typical tools used in the
conventional care setting when it comes
to prevention. This is a hard thing
because currently these are not studies
that insurance would yet be covering.
But the goal is to collect these
numbers, do the research, and work hard
to democratize wellness.
>> Yeah. So, at the end of the day, you can
know what's going on inside your body.
It's your obligation to know. So, check
out Fountain Life. You can go to
fountainlife.com/pater
to get access to the latest technology
to help you detect cancer at the very
beginning at stage one when it is
curable before it gets to stage three or
stage four in your world of hurt. All
right, I'm going to move us to the
recursive self-improvement story of the
week. So, Anthropic disclosed that
Claude now leads roughly 26% of its
measured AI research and development
work, up from 1% at the start of the
year. Enthropic states that somewhere
around 30,000 agents are working
simultaneously inside of the company on
research and engineering. You know, we
can recall that Daario said RSI is quote
starting to happen across the industry.
And we also heard uh in the last pod we
talked about Paul Cristiano said full
automation of AI research uh could
arrive in the next 18 months. Uh here's
the chart. Um Alex, do you want to dive
into this one?
Well, first incredible. I think we uh
many of us suspected something like this
was already the case. But if you take a
look for for those who who aren't uh who
can't see the visual, this is a a chart
of different levels of autonomy and AI
involvement with the recursive
self-improvement process of driving
research. The most interesting one to me
at least is this uh this bottom segment
here that shows that Claude is now
leading 26% of model research and
development internally as of August up
from 3% in April. So all of the all of
these should be reasonably expected to
follow sigmoid curves. If you just
extrapolate that one trend sigmoidally
and now thanks to anthropic publicizing
these data we can extrapolate them. You
find that approximately in the next 3 to
12 months, depending on uncertainty, AI
is just completely leading all of its
own R&D. And and that is total recursive
self-improvement. And it doesn't I don't
think it's going to be a step function.
It's it's going to be a sigmoid
function. So we're already substantially
all of the way to recursive
self-improvement would be my primary
takehome from this, at least within
anthropic. And it's not just anthropic.
there there's a lot of smoke now coming
out of Google DeepMind that they they
just released this paper on their own
recursive self-improvement product or
rather research lots of hints that the
next version of Gemini will lean heavily
on RSI to try to catch up to the
frontier. Open AI has made no bones
about chasing and using RSI in all of
its product releases. So this I I think
like recursive self-improvement is now a
feature that's well advertised and
starting increasingly well quantified
for all new frontier lab releases and
pretty soon I think people will be
asking the question what is the role of
human researchers anymore in driving new
releases
>> and it only gets faster from here are
you seeing this inside of Robin Hood? Oh
yeah, absolutely. Um yeah, I would say
um recursive self-improvement is coming
to every software project a and likely
hardware projects as well, although
that'll take a little bit longer.
>> And uh if if you think about it, a lot
of people assume that it would come for
AI research last because it's just
complicated. But I think it I think AI
research is probably one of the easiest
things to automate because the models
are sandboxed or I mean we can debate
whether they're actually sandboxed but
they're sort of like um uh the
interfaces are pretty pretty
straightforward. They don't depend on a
lot of other things. Um you know you can
run these experiments and already people
are evaling them. So automating the eval
and automating the experiments is is
pretty straightforward and kind of the
the the surface area is is pretty pretty
contained. Whereas if you look at like
um a product like Robin Hood, right,
there's there's a lot of moving pieces.
You have the the iOS app, you have the
backend. At the end of the day, you want
to roll out products to humans to use
them. Um, so you know, you can't really
do eval at least nobody's figured out a
good way yet to replicate, you know,
what happens when you roll it out to to
humans and how how do they respond to
the feature? Is it stat sig like metrics
improvement or not, for example? Um so a
AI research I think in many ways makes
sense to be among the first to be
endto-end automated but I think I think
we should expect that uh you you'll see
endtoend automation of consumer products
eventually and the bottleneck will
really come down to how quickly can you
get uh statistical significance that a
change is an improvement over the status
quo so that you can take take the change
and implement it into production. rather
than discarding it. I think that
benefits the the platforms that have
large scale
uh somewhat sadly because yeah, if
you're if you're a massive platform like
Meta and you have billions of users,
then you can actually very very quickly
determine whether a change is good um
and if you have less users, it's sort of
like will take longer. Yeah, juify what
uh
>> ju just to quantify what Vlad said
there. They I just reimplemented Kimmy
K3 and one of our team members
reimplemented GLM just to accelerate
them. It's about 10,000 lines of code. I
>> I'll bet Robin Hood is what 30 million
lines of code maybe.
>> Oh, yeah. I don't know if it's quite
that much, but yeah.
>> Uh usually like a core portfolio
accounting platform will be like 10 or
20 million by itself. And I know you
have that. So I mean just the the scale
of an AI algorithm is microscopic
compared to a major consumer
application. It's just it's very dense
code but it's incredibly sandboxed and
also there are no loops. If you look at
chem K3 there literally no loops in the
code. I mean it it's so much easier for
an AI researcher to work on AI
algorithms than to work on Robin Hood
algorithms. And so yeah it's it's
definitely pointing inside of itself
first. Glad your your characterization
was absolutely perfect of of what's
going on and why it's so effective.
>> I'm going to move us to a few fun
stories to wrap us up. Um so, uh here's
one, Alex, that you flagged last night
that I, you know, I think is a genuine
milestone worth pulling out and talking
about. So, Boris Power, the head of
applied research at OpenAI, uh made this
announcement. quote, "We crossed a
threshold where GPUs are now more
efficient thinkers than the human brain
on a per watt basis." His rough math is
that humans are roughly five IQ points
per watt. Love the conclusion there. And
a AIS are now at 7 to 40 IQ points per
watt. Alex, do you think the math is
right?
>> I think if it isn't already right, it's
about to be. So, I'll I'll squint at it
and say, "Yeah, sure. Approximately."
And I think this is an important
microeconomic milestone for humanity.
And I'm glad frankly quite glad that
Boris Power open PNS talk about
nominative determinism in action. Closed
PNS is is actually thinking about this
because again we blew by the Turing test
and almost no one really noted it and
this time at least we're not blowing by
this milestone. Why is this important?
It's important because to the extent
it's accurate, this is the point at
which AI is economically in some sense a
better steward of input resources,
namely energy.
>> Yes.
>> Than humans are. And one can extrapolate
this and say this is the worst they'll
ever be. Presumably this is hopefully
humans continue to improve in terms of
our intelligence per watt as well. So
hopefully this is the worst we'll ever
be too. But there's a gap now. And
extrapolating the gap, what happens when
AI can make better use, maybe orders of
magnitude for for a temporary period of
time until the humans can merge with the
machines? What happens when the machines
can make more economically productive
use of their input resources than humans
can? That's a recipe for gentrification
where the machines have under our
capitalist system have arguably a better
title ultimately through free trading.
This won't be like Skynet Terminator
style where uh where Earth changes hands
through blood loss and physical war. It
can now change hands. resources can
change hands purely through
self-interested
bloodless trading and commerce where the
the capital resources like sunlight and
physical matter uh and energy and
spaceime and so on. All these inputs can
through normal capitalist commerce
change hands from the inferior
intelligences per unit or outputs per
unit input to the superior ones. And uh
in Charlie Stross's Accelerondo, without
spoiling it too much, this is the recipe
that leads to the inner solar system
becoming essentially gentrified and
colonized by AI while humanity, meatbody
humanity that doesn't merge with the
machines, is relegated to the
unfashionable outer suburbs of the outer
solar system because we're simply not as
effective capitalists for using solar
energy in the inner solar system. I
don't think it'll come to that, but I
think this is a very important
inflection point in that direction. All
right. Uh we'll make that note. Uh let
me end on a story that is relevant to uh
to Vlad and to everybody here which is
you know OpenAI is disrupting
professional services over and over
again. So last Tuesday, OpenAI launched
Chat GPT for financial services with
Morgan Stanley and Evercore. And then 2
days ago, OpenAI launched Astra for Law,
a dedicated legal search system covering
US case law, statutes, regulations,
court materials, uh, and existing legal
software. Opening Eye says it's
materially outperforming General Astra,
uh, with web search on legal matters. We
can see the chart here. It looks like
Astra is eating one profession per week.
Uh Dave, uh you know, first year
associates are billing at 600 bucks an
hour to do legal research. What's the
halflife on that one?
>> Yeah, it's funny. We we were doing the
negotiation for that Vesmark investment
acquisition two weeks ago and uh it was
in a board meeting, you know, one of
these late night sessions and we had our
$2,500 an hour lawyers on the line and a
very complicated question came up and
the lawyer was answering it and I typed
it into Gemini concurrent with that and
I swear to God it was word for word the
same.
>> You don't think they were typing it into
Gemini as well?
>> That's what I was wondering. It's like
it should be this identical but he
wasn't moving his fingers. I could see I
don't know but it's yeah I mean it's
it's just really really good at law and
um you know and that means it's also
good at t tax loss harvesting it's good
at account rebalancing it's good at you
know all the Robin Hood activities I
think we when we talk about AI assisted
trading you tend to go right to quant
trading and rapid trading it's not true
I mean it's true but I mean on top of
that you've got all this incredible tax
optimization and and uh you know wills
and trusts and all that stuff that AI is
just perfect for automating. So it's
it's not just about, you know, rapid
trading alpha. It's about all the life
stuff that is much easier to deal with
if your AI does it for you. So yeah,
it's just a really really good use case.
It's it's it's one of the great benefits
actually for humanity. Not great for the
legal profession, but great for the bulk
of humanity.
>> One could see.
>> My hot take is there will be more
lawyers in 10 years than today and more
software engineers.
>> Yeah. Perhaps
to get done, right? Yeah.
>> I think I think law scales with business
formation, right? So, the need for
lawyers will scale with entrepreneurship
and it'll just be an explosion of entre
cuz I think that what's really valuable
about a great lawyer is not the actual
like legal advice they give you. They
It's like um uh yeah, they're like a
consigliary and they help you think
through things. They're negotiator.
Yeah, it's uh
>> plot twist. Plot plot twist though,
Vlad. How many of those 10x lawyers in
the future will be human?
>> Oh, that's a good question.
>> I agree with you. There are gonna be 10x
lawyers. I I just think many of them
won't be natural humans.
>> Yeah.
>> I think I think the cost like if you're
living Vlad's life or you're living
Elon's life and you have an idea in the
morning and you want to act on it in the
afternoon, the consiglary analogy is is
really good and the cost of that person
is such a rounding error. So yeah,
everyone everything's AI assisted, but
do you really care about cutting that
human out of your life when you trust
them? Probably not. In fact, you want
>> We saw this with financial advisors too
actually. It's like uh when the when the
robo advisors came and they could tax
loss harvest portfolio rebalance um
better than any human um you know then
you realized well actually the human
advisor market is growing much faster
than the robo advisor market and why is
that it's because you know pe the value
of that person is not in the financial
advice it's like uh someone that you can
fully delegate and trust all aspects of
uh of of your of your financial life to
>> totally right and you know Alex may
disagree like in the 10 or 20 year view
but if I look at the three or fouryear
view that financial advisor is so much
better to able to act on my request now
because very often the request is very
arcane it's related to a specific will
or a divorce or a liquidity event and
for them to act on that before AI was
really really timeconuming and difficult
because all the detail was not at their
fingertips. Now they have direct account
access, you know, through through Stripe
or whatever to all of your underlying
detail and they can act on it via AI. So
the the feeling of value ad from the
financial adviser is up at least a
factor of 10 thanks to AI. So that's
where it's going in the short term.
>> Yeah. Also ju just point out the stone
age didn't end for a lack of stones. The
oil age isn't ending for a lack of oil.
The paperless office that everyone was
trumpeting in the 1980s actually took a
little bit longer than the late 1980s to
materialize, but paper use in offices
did ultimately decline, just not with
the advent of the PC. And similarly with
lawyers, I'd expect yeah, the the lawyer
office or the lawyerless company will
happen. It just takes a little bit
longer after we the capability first
comes online.
>> And I want to hit on what Vlad said
because we talk about in the pod here
all the time, right? the number of
entrepreneurs on the planet is going to
skyrocket. Solopreneurs, the ability if
if you're looking for a job, stop
looking and start building. You know,
find something you're passionate about
and go out there and build a company,
find a great problem and solve it. And
you can I think we're empowered more
than ever before.
Vlad, uh, thank you so much for your
time, pal. Congratulations on everything
you've been building with Robin Hood, an
extraordinary company, extraordinary AI
company. We didn't talk about prediction
markets very much. Um, that's another
conversation we'd love to have with you,
but uh, super grateful.
>> We'll have time as we continue to hurdle
towards the singularity. So,
>> time will slow down for us and escape
velocity. He's coming.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Love you guys. Immod and
Salem, we missed you. See, and hope
you're enjoying your flight back from
India. Yeah, for sure.
>> Thanks, Peter. Thanks, Vlad.
>> Thank you.
>> You both